revolvermaps.com 2019-07-28

# Legal | RevolverMaps - Free 3D Visitor Maps

## Privacy Policy

This privacy policy has been created to point out how the company (Karma Implementor) running this web content protects the privacy of it's users. The following sections describe how and for what purpose data of users of this website on the one hand and data of users of the widget service one the other hand is processed and used. 

### 1\. Person in Charge

Responsible for data processing on this website is Karma Implementor, c/o: Daniel Seifert, Straße der Nationen 12, 09111 Chemnitz, Germany, email: contact@revolvermaps.com, phone: +49 371 233 80 316. 

### 2\. General Information

  * The services hosted by revolvermaps.com do not require a registration. 
  * The services hosted by revolvermaps.com are free of charge. 
  * No non-public data collected by the revolvermaps.com servers is shared with third parties. Data processing and data storage are limited to the purpose of providing the services described in this document. 
  * Privacy information on client side third party advertising integration is available in section 9.3 below. 

### 3\. Servers

The RevolverMaps servers are located in Frankfurt, Germany. 

A basic principle at revolvermaps.com is to keep the server configuration secure while running the minimum of required software and services. 

### 4\. IP Addresses

In order to communicate over a network a server needs to know the IP address of a client and vice versa. For instance, if your browser requests a file or other resource from a server under the domain revolvermaps.com, the IP address of your internet connection must be transmitted to this server due to the nature of the underlying [TCP/IP protocol](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transmission_Control_Protocol). 

#### 4.1 Processing and Storage of IP Addresses

All RevolverMaps servers treat IP addresses as a transient information processed in volatile memory only. Any nonvolatile storage like the logging of IP addresses is deactivated on all revolvermaps.com servers by default. Logging of IP addresses may be activated temporarily when it's neccessary for debugging purposes or when it's required to keep a stable and secure server operation for instance. In such cases IP addresses will be deleted as soon as they are no longer required. This occasional logging of IP addresses is for purposes of legitimate interests in accordance with Article 6(1)(f) GDPR. 

#### 4.2 Geolocation and Anonymized IP Addresses for Geolocation

Geolocation is performed on a city level. For RevolverMaps it is technically impossible to gain more accurate position data (like street names and house numbers) due to the method of geolocation and the available data: 

For the determination of the location of a connected client (see widget service) it's anonymized internet IP address is matched against a local database on a RevolverMaps server. The result is an estimation. Furthermore only the first 3 octets of an IPv4 address are used for the geolocation, the last octet is stripped. IPv6 addresses will be truncated to a prefix length of 64 bits before the location lookup. The trailing 64 bits are stripped. This practice lowers the precision of the geolocation additionally. Being transformed to a location information on a city level in this way, the result cannot be used to identify a person or an internet connection. The described data processing is required for the delivery of the RevolverMaps service and is for purposes of legitimate interests in accordance with Article 6(1)(f) GDPR. 

### 5\. Log Files

If a file is requested from a RevolverMaps server, the following information may be stored for 7 days: 

  * Time and date of the request 
  * The requested file / resource 
  * The HTTP statuscode (OK, NOT FOUND etc.) 
  * The amount of data being transfered 
  * The HTTP referer (the source from which you came to this website) if available and as available. The availability depends on browser settings, metadata (configuration) of the referring website and other factors. 
  * The user-agent string carrying information about your web browser like the name and version of your browser 
  * Information about your operating system like it's name and it's version 

The logged information can be used by Karma Implementor for debugging purposes, internal statistics, quality assurance but will not be published or shared. 

### 6\. Security / HTTPS

The whole RevolverMaps website is accessible through TLS secured connections (HTTPS). Using the world wide web you should generally prefer secure connections over unsecured connections. This ensures that you are connected to the authorized server and avoids data manipulation and data skimming on the route between your client (e.g. your browser) and the server. 

### 7\. Data Processing when Contacting RevolverMaps

Personal data - at least the email address - is stored once an email is sent to revolvermaps.com using an email address provided at this website. Further personal data may be part of the content of the particular email. Data from emails is solely used for the processing of your request. Legal basis for the processing of data from emails is Article 6(1)(f) GDPR, the legitimate interest to reply to your request. The conversation data is kept for future requests. Please see section 8 regarding your rights. 

An order processing agreement exists between Karma Implementor and the email service provider. 

### 8\. Your Rights

  * Right of access by the data subject (Art. 15 GDPR) 
  * Right to rectification (Art. 16 GDPR) 
  * Right to erasure ('Right to be forgotten', Art. 17 GDPR) 
  * Right to restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR) 
  * Right to data portability (Art. 20 GDPR) 
  * Right to object (Art. 21 GDPR) 
  * Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority (Art. 77 GDPR) 

### 9\. Information Collection when Visiting this Website

The following information applies to the use of this website (usually by opening a page under www.revolvermaps.com in your web browser). **Please find privacy information about the widget serviceunder (10).**

#### 9.1 General Information on Cookies

A cookie is a small amount of data that can be stored by a website on the clients hard drive containing arbitrary information associated with the particular browser instance. A website can define the lifetime of a cookie. Some cookies are used to keep user information during a browser session. Such cookies are typically deleted after the browser has been closed. Cookies can also be used across browser sessions being available for a virtually infinite period of time or until they are manually deleted by the user. Such cookies can be used to keep user specific website settings or to identify browsers and potentially even users. 

Most wellknown browsers support cookies and provide options to disable the cookie service, to clear all cookie data and to inspect the cookies set by a certain domain. Generally browsers provide the option to automatically clear all cookies on exit. 

Please find instructions to cookie settings for the most popular browser under the following links: 

#### 9.2 RevolverMaps Cookies

www.revolvermaps.com uses HTTP cookies to improve the usability of the website. Therefore cookies will be accessed (created, read and written) only on the client side to store and retrieve several user settings. All necessary cookie action is handled by client side JavaScript code. Due to their technical characteristics cookies will be send to www.revolvermaps.com with every page request but no information from cookies will be read, collected and stored at the server. To avoid plaintext transmission of cookies you should use secure connections to the revolvermaps.com servers. 

This website can be used without cookies. 

The following table lists the cookies set and read by www.revolvermaps.com: 

Cookie Name| Current Value (N/A if the cookie is not set)| Where at www.revolvermaps.com?| Description  
---|---|---|---  
_w3d| | live statistics page| width of the 3D globe ( _GLobe_ ) on the live statistics page  
_wdd| | live statistics page| width of the 2D map on the live statistics page  
wloc| | live statistics page| width of the _Locations_ table on the live statistics page  
cookieconsent| | global| relevant for end users from the EU: don't display the cookie consent message if set  
  
You can use the following button to delete the cookies listed in the table above. This procedure may not work in all browsers. After the deletion you should check the table again. If the values don't change to N/A you have to clear the cookies in your browser settings. 

#### 9.3 Non-Personalized Advertising with Google Adsense / Third Party Cookies

In order to provide a free service RevolverMaps is funded by an advertising-supported revenue model. Providing a secure and stable service is in accordance with Article 6(1)(f) GDPR for purposes of legitimate interests. 

This website uses Google Adsense as a third-party advertising service to serve ads when you visit certain revolvermaps.com webpages. Google Adsense is a service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. 

Google is [certified by the privacy shield framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI) and thus guarantees to comply with the european privacy law. 

The advertisements displayed on this website are not personalized: User tracking for purposes like retargeting is deactivated in the Google Adsense settings. Advertisements are not displayed basing on user profiles or prior activities on other websites. In addition, ads are displayed from the Google Adsense network only, ads from third party vendors are disabled. Advertisements may still be targeted based on contextual information (the topic of the website), the general user location and current search terms. Your interests, search history and browsing history are not analyzed for ad targeting. Thus, ads on this website may be less useful for you. As a third party vendor Google processes user data like clicks on ads and your IP address. Your information may still be used purposes such as to measure the effectiveness of advertising, fraud protection and abuse protection. 

Please find more information on how Google uses information as well as options for objection and settings in the Google privacy policy (<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>) and in the Google ads settings (<https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>). 

#### 9.4 DOM Storage

Similar to HTTP cookies DOM storage is a method used for storing data persistently in a web browser. In constrast to HTTP cookies data from DOM storage is not submitted with the HTTP request header. Compared to cookies this technology provides a considerably enhanced storage capacity. 

Revolvermaps.com uses DOM storage to keep more complex user preferences on client side. 

Every wellknown browser provides the option to clear all persistent data. Normally DOM storage is cleared together with cookies. Most browsers provide options to disable the DOM storage service and to inspect the data stored by a certain domain. 

This website can be used without dom storage. 

The following table lists details of DOM storage usage by www.revolvermaps.com: 

Key| Lifetime| Where at www.revolvermaps.com?| Description  
---|---|---|---  
_dmPref| persistent| live statistics page| preferred display mode (2D od 3D). Required for the _Locations_ view.  
_2dm| persistent| live statistics page| 2D display mode: stores the last selected 2D mode (new map ( _mapZ_ ) or classic map)  
_3dm| persistent| live statistics page| 3D display mode: stores the last selected 3D mode (new globe ( _GLobe_ ) or classic globe)  
websiteversion| persistent| live statistics page| stores the prefered site view (desktop/mobile)  
livemapz[...]settings| persistent| live statistics page| stores user preferences for the 2D map ( _mapZ_ ) like filter settings etc.  
livermgl[...]settings| persistent| live statistics page| stores user preferences for the 3D globe ( _GLobe_ ) like filter settings etc.  
bars[...]settings| persistent| live statistics page| stores sort column, sort order and view mode for the _Locations_ view  
_m[...]| persistent| live statistics page| stores the map image used for the visualizations at the live stats page  
_c[...]| persistent| live statistics page| stores the dot color used for the visualizations at the live stats page  
rm_disabled| persistent| global| RevolverMaps counters are disabled for this website when set to _1_  
rmSetupPreviewBGColor| session| setup pages| stores the color of the preview area  
rmSetupSampleBGChecked| session| setup pages| stores the setting for the sample background of the preview area  
  
#### 9.5 Use of the RevolverMaps Service on this Website

The RevolverMaps service provided by this website is also used on this website for demonstration purposes and to obtain and share elementary and anonymous visitor information with all users and visitors. Detailed information is provided by this document. You can disable the visitor registration on this website: 

RevolverMaps is currently enabled on this website.

#### 9.6 External Links

This website is configured to reduce the HTTP referrer information to the origin portion (https://www.revolvermaps.com or http://www.revolvermaps.com). When you click on a link to an internal or external site this information may be sent to the target host but not the complete URL. This applies to the use of modern browsers. 

### 10\. Widget Service and Public Statistics

#### 10.1 Description

RevolverMaps provides visitor map widgets for the use on websites. The widgets show the locations of visitors of a website using the service. The determination of the location bases on anonymized IP addresses as described under 4.2. (Geolocation and Anonymized IP Addresses for Geolocation). Every widget contains a link to a public statistics page at www.revolvermaps.com. This page exists to provide more detailed information coming along with better accessibility. 

#### 10.2 Installation and Functional Principle

In order to make use of the widget service the administrator of a website installs a piece of code which requests the resources that are required for the correct function of the service every time the page is being loaded by a user. These resources are for instance JavaScript programs, images and location data to be displayed by a particular widget. 

The widget code is freely available without the need of submitting personal data. An unique token (a combination of digits and letters) is installed with the widget code. This token is used to associate visitor data with a particular website. 

In addition to the loading of resources the client side code sends a request that is used to register the client and to perform the geolocation as described. The result of the geolocation is stored in a database and is displayed by widgets and on the live statistics page. 

#### 10.3 Data

The following data is stored and visible to everyone. Please note that the storage of per location data is limited to one data record in an area of 40km². When new data is available for such a cell, the old data will be replaced: 

**Per location data:**

  * The coordinates, rounded to grid cells of 40km²; used to draw location markers 
  * The location name (city, region, country) 
  * The time and date of the request 
  * The total number of visits per location, aggregated for all users 

**Aggregated data (not coupled with location data):**

  * The total number of visits, aggregated for all users 

In addition the URL of the website containing a widget is sent to RevolverMaps and stored privately on the RevolverMaps servers for 1 hour. This data can be used internally for debugging purposes and abuse prevention and is never published or shared. This data collection happens for the purposes of legitimate interests in accordance with Article 6(1)(f) GDPR. 

Data exchange is limited to the client browser executing widget code and RevolverMaps servers. The protocol of the user website is also used for connections to the RevolverMaps servers. Thus users of the service are encouraged to secure their websites with TLS to secure these connections. 

**It is important to state that:**

  * As long as the website using the service does not leak sensitive information (for instance as part of it's URLs), the RevolverMaps service is technically incapable of identifying users as persons. RevolverMaps has no access to data that would be required and does not collect such data. 
  * The RevolverMaps service is free of cookies and does not track users across websites. The system is not designed to identify users by unique id's from cookies or other storage technics. 

#### 10.4 Data Protection Notice

Users have to disclose the use of the widget service in their privacy policy. The user is responsible for the correct content of the notice. It is recommended to specify the purpose of the use and the data being collected and processed (see this document). It is furthermore recommended to provide a link to this document: 

_https://www.revolvermaps.com/?target=privacy_

#### 10.5 Opt-out

As a user of the widget service you may want to implement an opt-out button on your website. Here is a sample implementation, you can add it for example to your privacy policy. The code can be modified to fit your needs: 

**1\. The code for the opt-out button:**

**2\. Additionally you have to modify your widget code**

Place your widget code _INSIDE_ the single quotes ( _var code=' <script>...</script>'_ )! The variable _alternative_ can be a message to be displayed if the user has opted out the service. Additionally it could link to your opt-out button: 

_This privacy policy was updated on July 3, 2019_
